64. Concrete's Glowing Future We can all agree that concrete buildings are
almost universally ugly. Concrete may be a cheap and convenient building material, but
it's not going to win any beauty contests. That, however, could be about to change. A
Mexican scientist named Jose Carlos Rubio Avalos has invented a type of concrete that,
amazingly, glows in the dark. Avalos accomplished this by inserting cells that absorb light
into cement, a key ingredient in concrete. By day the concrete absorbs light, and when
the sun goes down, it begins to glow. It's said to work even on cloudy days. Currently
Avalos's concrete can emit blue or green light, but he's working on versions that
will glow white, red, and even purple. Avalos's invention has city governments and architects
very excited. Having glowing buildings could save cities millions of dollars on electricity,
and architects will have a whole new visual tool to experiment with. Can you imagine how
beautiful the buildings of the future might be, covered in glowing rainbow patterns? There
is however one problem, the cost. Glow in the dark concrete is currently five times
more expensive to produce than regular concrete. But there is no need to build an entire building
out of glowing concrete. Instead, existing structures could be coated with a thin layer
of Avalos's special material. This would make creating a glow in the dark building
a lot cheaper. But how often, you might ask, would you have to reapply the concrete? Would
it be worth the cost and the effort? Fear not. According to Avalos, his concrete can
retain its glowing effect for around a hundred years. That's free light for a century. Thanks
to Jose Avalos, the future of concrete looks very bright indeed.